CURRICULUM VITAE



CAREER SUMMARY

More than 15 years of service with many varieties of job responsibilities. Handling and managing Call Center Department, pro-active monitoring business process through Quality Assurance Department, explore the creativity in Marketing Department (incl. Marketing Promo, Sales & Telesales, Product Catalog-offline & online, Reward & Redemption, Special Event, Customer Retention & Loyalty Management), developing positive cooperation with business and non business institution through Business Development & Partnership Department. And now I'm focusing on Business Development and Customer Engagement through Customer Relationship Management with enlarging my competencies in One-to-One Marketing/CRM with the intention to know customer better and creating lifetime engagement between customer and the business.

QUALIFICATION

- 1. Experienced in customer engagement (customer relationship management), partnership engagement & business development for consumer retail business
- 2. Experienced in customer service & call center (inbound & outbond)
- 3. Experienced in marketing & sales program, promotion campaign
- 4. Experienced in creating customer life cycle activities (customer retention & loyalty management), activation campaign (incl. using telesales channel)
- 5. Experienced in reward & redemption promo, product catalog
- 6. Experienced in business development & partnership for banks and non banks, B2B partnership
- 7. Experienced in card business as a payment tools
- 8. Experienced in quality assurance process, operation & internal audit

RECENT PROJECT in PT Mega Mahadana Hadiya (Mahadya):

- Define and developing new CRM System (system, database, usage program, handling complaint): creating program to increase transaction of customer member & brand awareness, managing customer database, handling customer complaint and managing membership operation
- Creating & maintaining partnership program for all business line of retail business in PT Mahadya (FMCG and F&B business): set up marketing, sales, & campaign of partnership joint promotion

PROJECTS COMPLETED in PT Bank Negara Indonesia (Persero) Tbk.:

- Enlarging portfolio of Co Brand & Affinity Cards (from March 2010- September 2014)
- Developing new variant of Co Branding BNI-LOTTE Mart Platinum Credit Card (2013)
- Developing Co Branding BNI-Garuda Indonesia Credit Card (2013)
- Developing Co Branding BNI-Chelsea FC (2013)
- Developing Co Branding BNI-Ferrari SpA (2013)
- Define & develop Co Branding BNI bank bjb Card (2013)
- Define & develop Co Branding BNI Rakuten Card, BNI Citilink Card (2013)
- Define & develop Customer Life Cycle Management Plan (MasterCard Advisors) for Co Branding Credit Card (2012)
- Developing new variant of Co Branding BNI Community (WWF, Bike to Work, PVG Golf, Portal HR, AUSCI (2011-2012)

- Developing new variant of Co Branding BNI University (UDAYANA, UNSOED, UNMUL, UNNES, UNSYIAH and other state Universities.) (2011).
- Pre-development Online Merchandising Catalog (November 2010)
- Pro Activation by Telesales channel (May 2010)
- Develop Online Redemption point reward system and mechanism (September 2009)
- ISO 9001: 2000 Quality Management System (2004)

WORK EXPERIENCES

September 2014 to Present

Company : PT Mega Mahadana Hadiya (Mahadya) - Trakindo Group

Position : CRM & Partner Manager

Roles and Responsibilities:

• Responsible for Customer Relationship Management (CRM) of membership card (using existing system):

- ➤ Creating retention campaigns for member, from conceptualization through to postevent analysis (ideas, proposal preparation, overseeing the production process, overseeing execution, and reporting back results)
- > Managing data of customer (membership card)
- > Managing stock of card member and starter pack collateral
- > Managing marketing communication of membership card
- Managing and supervising front liners to deliver member's satisfaction
- > Monitoring the operation of CRM's system include identifying and mitigation of potential problem thus providing problem solution
- > Develop new CRM system (set up strategic blue print of CRM)
- Responsible for creating partnership cooperation
 - > Creating and managing partnership programs for membership card
 - > Creating and managing partnership program for each lines of business in Mahadya such as creating usage (sales) & promotion program
 - > Managing marketing communication of the program
 - > Managing internal system and operation
 - > Monitoring and analyzing partnership programs results
 - > Maintaining portfolio of partnership
 - > Managing complaint

PERIOD: March 2011 to September 2014

COMPANY: PT Bank Negara Indonesia (Persero) Tbk.

POSITION: Business Development Co Brand & AffinityCredit Card Manager

Roles and Reponsibilites:

> New Product

- Define new product concept e.g basic features, special feature/loyalty features, target market, commercial deal etc.
- Define acquisition strategy
- Define 1st usage program strategy
- Define flow process of application processing
- Define card's features enhancement and coordinate with IT Department for system development
- Define card and marketing collateral design and launching event
- Coordinatewith Purchasing Department for blank card procurement, marketing collateral production
- Coordinate with Legal Department for legal and business agreement
- Coordinare with Policy Department for forming SOP/technical procedures, reporting to Bank Indonesia

- Define project charter for new product e.g enrollment to pricipal, system development, UAT, marketing communication, launching, etc.
- Overseing and monitoring new product Define and ensure all the process on track
- New product review's weekly
- Responsible for new card's growth

Exsiting Product

- Responsible for growth of usage volume Co Brand & Affinity credit card products
- Responsible for growth of number Co Brand & Affinity credit card products
- Planning short and long term of usage program for Co Brand & Affinity credit card products
- Planning short and long term of acquisition program for Co Brand & Affinity credit card products
- Creating special/tactical usage program of Co Brand & Affinity credit card products
- Creating special event for acquisition program & special program acquisition (incl.motivation program) of Co Brand & Affinity credit card products
- Review credit card's features of Co Brand & Affinity products
- Weekly & monthly performance review of Co Brand & Affinity products
- Establish and maintain a positive relationship and cooperation with partner
- Quarter review of Co Brand& Affinity performance with partner
- Foster a well-trained and motivated staff
- Conduct employee performance reviews
- Scheduled and conduct department's meeting
- Performance report accountability to AVP & VP of Debit, Prepaid & Co Brand Card

May 2009 to March 2011

Company : PT Bank Negara Indonesia (Persero) Tbk. CARD BUSINESS DIVISION

Position : Marketing & Development Manager

(Loyalty, Anti Attrition & Merchandising Manager)

Roles and Responsibilities:

Activation :

- Increase number of card activation, plastic & usage activation (activation rate)
- Planning short and long term programs for Card Activation based on Customer Life Cycle Management Plan
- Creating Early Activation programs by all channels of plastic activation
- Creating Usage Activation programs by all channels of usage activation
- Ensuring that all program of Early Activation will increase the plastic card activation
- Ensuring that all program of Usage Activation will reduce dormant card and increase sales volume
- Creating motivation program for activation agents
- Develop performance and productivity of activation agents
- Coordinate with delivery department for card delivery status, received by cardholder
- Coordinate with call center department for the execution of early activation call (incl. preparing & creating tools of handling calls for activation such as standard script for welcoming, inform the benefit and offering the program)
- Coordinate with application processing department to ensuring the validity of new customer's data
- Coordinate with risk department for invalid data
- Foster a well-trained and motivated staff
- Conduct employee performance reviews
- Scheduled and conduct department's meeting
- Performance report accountability to AVP & VP of Marketing & Development

> Anti Attrition:

- Decreasing number of attrition (increasing anti attrition rate)
- Planning short and long term programs to prevent/reduce voluntary attrition
- Creatinganti attrition programs by all channels of attrition's request
- Creatinganti attrition programs based on Matrix of Anti Attrition
- Creating motivation program for anti attrition agents
- Develop performance and productivity of anti attrition agents
- Coordinate with call center department for the execution of anti attrition call (incl. preparing &creating tools of handling of call's request for attrition such as standard script, offering the program, etc)
- Foster a well-trained and motivated staff
- Conduct employee performance reviews
- Scheduled and conduct department's meeting
- Performance report accountability to AVP & VP of Marketing & Development

> Loyalty Programs:

- Planning short and long term programs for loyalty programs based on customer's profile and behavior
- Identifying market & customer characteristics/segmentation
- Creating program for increase customer's loyalty & usage
- Creatingprograms for birthday greetings, seasons greetings, complimentary magazine/voucher/ticket, seasonal event, etc
- Ensure that the loyalty program will give an impact to sales volume and increase the customer's loyalty
- Establish and maintain a positive relationship and cooperation with partner
- Foster a well-trained and motivated staff
- Conduct employee performance reviews
- Scheduled and conduct department's meeting
- Performance report accountability to AVP & VP of Marketing & Development

> Rewards Point

- Managing the rewards point
- Planning short and long term programs for reward point programs
- Creating programs for redemption rewards point by online redemption and offline redemption
- Ensuring that the redemption program will increase sales volume and the customer's loyalty
- Coordinate with merchant department for preparing all the online redemption system
- Coordinate with procurement department for preparing all the offline redemption programs (incl. monthly rewards catalogue)
- Continuously create and develop the channel of redemption points
- Establish and maintain a positive relationship and cooperation with partner
- Foster a well-trained and motivated staff
- Conduct employee performance reviews
- · Scheduled and conduct department's meeting
- Performance report accountability to AVP & VP of Marketing & Development

March 2008 to April 2009

Company : PT Bank Negara Indonesia (Persero) Tbk. CARD BUSINESS DIVISION

Position : Marketing & Development Manager (Usage Features Management Manager)

> Features

- Planning short and long term programs for maximizing usage from credit card features
- Managing selling channel of features product, Telesales and Non Telesales channel (incl. direct mail, flyer, etc)
- Creating program to increase customer's usage in product features, recurring and non recurring features, installment and non installment features

- Negotiating with partner for recurring programs and installment programs
- Coordinate with call center department for the execution of selling product features (incl. preparing data, develop the system, etc
- Coordinate with policy department to evaluate the product features policy and procedures
- Ensuring that every process of selling product features are comply with the policy and procedures
- Ensuring that the features program will give an impact to sales volume and increase the customer's loyalty
- Continuously evaluate and develop every selling channel of product features
- Foster a well-trained and motivated staff
- Conduct employee performance reviews
- Scheduled and conduct department's meeting
- Performance report accountability to AVP & VP of Marketing & Development

Merchandising

- Planning short and long term programs for merchandising sales
- · Creating programs for merchandising catalog, non catalog and bazaar
- Negotiating with partner for merchandising programs such as type of products, fee, etc.
- Ensuring that every product in merchandising program are suitable with the customer's need and market trends
- Coordinate with marketing communication department for the design of the catalog and the event theme
- Coordinate with operation department for ensuring the purchase order and payment to partner are comply with the procedures
- Continuously create and develop the channel of merchandising transaction
- Foster a well-trained and motivated staff
- Conduct employee performance reviews
- Scheduled and conduct department's meeting
- Performance report accountability to AVP & VP of Marketing & Development

February 2007 - February 2008

Company : PT Bank Negara Indonesia (Persero) Tbk. CARD BUSINESS DIVISION

Position : Call Center Supervisor

> Managing call center activities

- Ensuring handling calls of call center agents comply with policy and procedures
- Ensuring handling calls of call center agents comply with service standard
- Ensuring handling calls of call center agents will increase customers satisfaction
- Managing transaction authority from call center agents
- Handling and analyzed customer's complaint
- Creating motivation program for call center agents
- Coordinate with business, supporting, and operation department for updating program information, system support, and operation process
- Continuously create and develop work flow process of call center activities
- Developing performance and productivity of call center agents
- Foster a well-trained and motivated staff
- Conduct employee performance reviews
- Performance report accountability to Manager & AVP of Call Center Department

November 2006 - January 2007

Company : PT Bank Negara Indonesia (Persero) Tbk.HUMAN RESORCES DIVISIONS

Position : Senior Assistant Manager

> Human Resources Policy and Procedures

- Review and analyze of human resources benefit and facilities, speciallyfor force majeure conditions
- Reports accountability to AVP of Human Resources Policy and Procedures

April 2005 - October 2006

Company : PT Bank Negara Indonesia (Persero) Tbk. HUMAN RESORCES DIVISIONS

Position : Scholarship Program

Human Resources Department PT Bank BNI (Persero) Tbk. as a scholarship university student, Magister ManajemenUniversitasIndonesia, Faculty of Economic, Majoring International Management

2003 - March 2005

Company: PT Bank Negara Indonesia (Persero) Tbk. CARD BUSINESS DIVISION

Position : Quality Assurance Officer

Service Quality System

- Continuously create and develop service level indicator for all process in card business
- Monitoring service level indicator achievement by all process in card business (monthly)
- Ensuring that all value chain of process comply with policy and procedures by internal audit activities
- Ensuring that all value chain of process comply with standard ISO 9001: 2000
- Conduct service meeting to management (monthly)
- Performance report to Manager of Quality Assurance

2002

Company: PT Bank Negara Indonesia (Persero) Tbk. CARD BUSINESS DIVISION

Position : Senior Call Center Officer

> Handling incoming calls

- Daily handling incoming calls from cardholder
- · Maintain transaction from cardholder's request
- Handling cardholder's complaint
- Ensuring that handling call activities comply with policy, procedures, and service standard
- Continuously create and develop tools for optimizing calls handling
- Performance reports accountability report to Call Center Supervisor

March 1999 - 2001

Company : PT Bank Negara Indonesia (Persero) Tbk. CARD BUSINESS DIVISION

Position : Call Center Officer

> Handling incoming calls

- Daily handling incoming calls from cardholder
- Maintain transaction from cardholder's request
- Handling cardholder's complaint
- Ensuring that handling call activities comply with policy, procedures, and service standard
- Continuously create and develop tools for optimizing calls handling
- Performance reports accountability report to Call Center Supervisor

EDUCATION BACKGROUND

Year graduated

1. Faculty of Economic, Magister Manajemen, University of Indonesia 2006 2. Faculty of Social & Political, University of Parahyangan, Bandung 1997

ON THE JOB TRAINING DEVELOPMENT & COURSES

June 2-3, 2016 : CRM Fundamentals Training - Inter System Asia

March 31, 2016 : Workshop Series #1: The One-to-One CRM Gap Analysis - Inter System

Asia

October 6-8, 2014 : Superior Service Skill For Head Office Training Program, PT Mega

Mahadana Hadiya (Mahadya)

July 12, 2014 : PROGRAM PEMELIHARAAN SERTIFIKASI MANAJEMEN RISIKO LEVEL 1 &

2, PT Bank Negara Indonesia (Persero) Tbk.

May 4, 2014 : Motivation for Leader Program
March 21, 2014 : Business & Industry Accumen
May 18, 2013 : Card Business Training Program

December 21, 2011 : Building Intrapreneur Spirit Training Program

July 19-22, 2010 : SERTIFIKASI MANAJEMEN RISIKO LEVEL 2, PT. Bank Negara Indonesia

(Persero) Tbk.

May 10-12, 2010 : SERTIFIKASI MANAJEMEN RISIKO LEVEL 1, PT. Bank Negara Indonesia

(Persero) Tbk.

March 3-6, 2010 : ENTERPRISE RISK MANAGEMENT & THE NEW CONSUMER

BANKINGSTRATEGY, The Blue Mountain Inc.

January 16, 2010 : TOEIC Certification

July 29, 2008 : EFFECTIVE HABITS for BUSINESS SUCCESS, Dunamis Organization

Services

April 28, 2008 : MALCOLM BALDRIGE CRITERIA for PERFORMANCE EXCELLENCE

CHAMPIONPT. Bank Negara Indonesia (Persero) Tbk.

June 11, 2007 : AWARENESS MALCOLM BALDRIGE CRITERIA for PERFORMANCE

EXCELLENCE PT. Bank Negara Indonesia (Persero) Tbk.

November 27, 2006 : KNOWING YOUR CUSTOMER & ANTI MONEY LAUNDRING, PT. Bank

Negara Indonesia (Persero) Tbk.

April, 2005 : SCHOLARSHIP PT. Bank Negara Indonesia (Persero) Tbk.

December 17, 2004 : SIX SIGMA WORKSHOP, AXON

February 11, 2004 : MANAGEMENT SERVICE EXCELLENCE TRAINING, PQMC.

December 31, 2003 : ENGLISH FOR BUSINESS COMMUNICATION

October 22, 2003 : ISO 9001:2000, PQMC

August 15, 2003 : CUSTOMER SERVICE EXCELLENCE, Academia Education & Training
June 28, 2002 : TFT. SERVICE EXCELLENCE, PT Bank Negara Indonesia (Persero) Tbk.
March 23, 2000 : SERVICE EXCELLENCE, PT Bank Negara Indonesia (Persero) Tbk.
March 29, 1999 : CALL CENTER TRAINING, PT Bank Negara Indonesia (Persero) Tbk.

CONTACT INFORMATION

Name : Ria Rahmawati

Address : Jl. Pengairan No 25, Pejompongan Jakarta 10210

Telephone : 021-5708624 Mobile phone : 0812 805 2575 WhatsApp : 0878 8347 0201

E-mail : rahmawati_ria@yahoo.com

rahmawati.r@gmail.com

Place/Date of Birth : Bandung, November 20th, 1974

Nationality : Indonesian Religion : Moslem

Marital Status : Married, 1 child

Availability : Immediately after notice period of 1 month

LANGUAGES

: Good Bahasa English : Good

HOBBIES, INTEREST & ACTIVITY Jogging Swimming Traveling Music & movies